aoi hoshi ni senritsu ga hashiru
a
o
i
ho
shi
ni
se
n
ri
tsu
ga
ha
shi
ru
A shudder runs over the blue planet
푸른 지구에 전율이 흐른다
kuroi arashi chikazuku toki
ku
ro
i
a
ra
shi
chi
ka
zu
ku
to
ki
It's the time the dark storm approaches
검은 폭풍이 닥쳐오는 순간
kokoro no oku de mezameru HERO
ko
ro
no
o
ku
de
me
za
ru
HE
RO
It's as if a hero is awakening on the inside
마음 속의 눈을 뜬 영웅들이여
tobitatsu no da furimukazu ni
to
bi
ta
tsu
no
da
fu
ri
mu
ka
zu
ni
Fly away and don't look back!
뒤돌아보지 말고 날아가라
DAGWON kagayake DAGWON
DA
G
WON
ka
ga
ya
ke
DA
G
WON
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Brave Command Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Dagwon... Shine on!! Dagwon!
다그온 빛나라!! 다그온
heiwa mamoru namae sa
he
i
wa
ma
mo
ru
na
ma
e
sa
The name that protects the peace
평화를 지키는 이름이다
DAGWON oretachi DAGWON
DA
G
WON
o
re
ta
chi
DA
G
WON
Dagwon! We are Dagwon!
다그온 우리는 다그온
yume wa zettai watasanai
yu
me
wa
ze
t
ta
i
wa
ta
sa
na
i
We will never hand over our dream
꿈은 절대로 넘겨줄 수 없다
afureru yuuki te ni shitai nara
a
fu
re
ru
yu
u
ki
te
ni
shi
ta
i
na
ra
To grab the overflowing courage
넘쳐흐르는 용기를 거머쥐고 싶다면
tsuyoku tsuyoku yuujou shinjiru koto sa
tsu
yo
ku
tsu
yo
ku
yu
u
jo
shi
n
ji
ru
ko
to
sa
We believe in our friendship firmly
우리 우정을 굳게 믿는 거다
kizutsuku koto mo osore wa shinai
ki
zu
tsu
ku
ko
to
mo
o
so
re
wa
shi
na
i
We are not afraid of getting hurt
상처입는 것도 두렵지 않아
mugendai no mirai wo egaku sono tame ni
mu
ge
n
da
i
no
mi
ra
i
wo
e
ga
ku
so
no
ta
me
ni
In order to reach that infinite future!
무한대의 미래를 그려내기 위해서라면
Brutal aliens escaped from the Space Prison Sargasso.
우주 감옥 사르갓소의 흉악한 우주인들
To protect the Earth from those evil hands, the brave high school students, Dagwon, keep fighting on to this day.
그 마수로부터 지구를 지키기 위해 오늘도 계속해서 싸우는 고등학생 용자 다그온
The result of their further power up is Dag Fire's Strength Fusion, Power Dagwon.
그들의 거듭되는 파워업이 바로 다그 파이어의 강력 합체 파워 다그온인 것이다
Sankai High School 58th Festival
산카이 고등학교 제 58회 학원제
That won't work.
이래선 안되잖아
Check the important part of the case.
케이스의 중요한 부분을 체크해 둬
-Yes, sir. Understood.
-Do it properly.
예, 알겠습니다 초상 현상 연구회
MONSTER
도깨비
MONSTER HOUSE
도깨비집
Supernatural Phenomenon
Research Club
초상현상 연구회
Perfect.
완벽해
I'm counting on you for tomorrow.
내일부터 잘 부탁해
Leave it to us.
맡겨만 두세요
For Ms. Maria, I'll do whatever even if I have to go through fire or water...
마리아 씨를 위해서라면 설령 불 속이든 물 속이든…
Do not forget that you'll void the debt!
말해 두겠는데 빚 진거 없던 걸로 해 준다고 한 약속 잊지 말라구
Sheesh, I know already.
정말… 알았다니까
Just do your best!
너도 잘 부탁해
You too.
정말…
Subject approaching! Standby for rehearsal.
실험 대상 발견!
리허설 준비해
A monster house?
도깨비집인가?
Welcome, vice principal!
자아~ 어서 오세요
교장 선생님
We're having a beta period.
지금 시험 기간 중이랍니다
No thanks, I don't like scary things.
아니, 나는 무서운 걸 싫어해서…
-Let's go together.
-Vice principal...
-제가 함께 가 드리지요
-교감 선생님…
Hmph, it is still a child's play.
흥, 어차피 애들 놀이일 뿐입니다
I'll make that bastard wet his pants!
짜식, 오줌 지려도 난 모른다
A School Festival Calls for a Storm
폭풍을 부르는 학원제
(Futtoba: spin off of the word buttobasu; to knock so hard that one is flown away)
Alien of Typhoon Futtoba Seijin
Appears
태풍 우주인 훗토바 성인
등장
I am suffering~
억~울~해~
It's alright. It's alright. It's nothing.
괜찮아, 괜찮아
뭐 이런 것 쯤이야
Th-this is...
이, 이건…
Don't worry. Someone's obviously hiding inside.
어차피, 누군가가 숨어있을 게 뻔합니다
Blood!
피를…!
Let me suck your blood!
피를 빨게 해 다오!
Was it scary?
무섭죠~?
Grandpa! What's wrong?
할아버지! 왜 그래요?
Maybe it was too much...
조금 심했나?
Are you alright, granpa?
괜찮아요, 할아버지?
How is it?
어떤가~?
-He- hey...
-V! V!
-이, 이봐요
-브이 브이
That bald old man won't be easy to deal with...
저 민둥머리 영감…
만만하게 볼 수 없겠는걸
-Should we shorten it a bit more?
-How about this?
-조금 더 줄여볼까?
-이정도?
But wouldn't it be risky if we do it?
하지만 더 줄이면 위험하지 않을까?
That's a good thing.
그게 좋은 거야
Yeah, yeah.
예이 예이
The sun isn't even going down yet.
해는 아직 중천이다
It's no time for a blood sucker to wander around, is it?
흡혈귀가 싸돌아다닐 시간이 아닐텐데?
The school cafeteria wasn't open.
학교 식당이 쉬더라구
I gotta drink fast.
빨리 안 마시면 죽을 것 같아
It opens tomorrow! Come again then!
개점은 내일이다!
그 때 다시 와라
Hmph, you cheapskate!
쳇, 구두쇠 같으니라고
It's totally not like you.
너답지 않은걸
(Teru Teru Bouzu: paper doll to which children pray for fine weather)
You making Teru Teru Bouzu?
테루테루보우즈라니 말이야
Save it for a rainy day. I'm preparing for just that.
유비무환 (備え有れば憂い無し)
저걸 대비한 거예요
The 15th Typhoon with enormous waves and influence is
대형에 파도의 세력을 지닌 태풍 15호는
still heading north with a slow speed of 10km.
여전히 매 10Km의 느린 속도로 북쪽을 향하고 있으며…
L
H
17th Typhoon
17호 태풍
Typhoon
태풍
Thankfully its route avoids Japan, but if it does reach land, it would be unfair to be unable to have the school festival.
진로는 벗어나고 있어서 걱정 없지만 만에 하나 상륙해서 학원제가 중지된다면 억울하잖아요
Everyone looks ambitious.
다들 정말 의욕이 넘치는구만
YAKISOBA HARUKA
볶음국수 하루카
Yakisoba Haruka?
볶음국수 하루카?
I guess I can help with yakisoba.
나도 뭐, 볶음국수 정도는…
Ijuuin?!
교감 선생님?!
How filthy! Please move!
에에이, 불결해!
거기서 비키세요
It's nothing to be mad about!
뭐 화낼 일은 아니잖아요?
I'll just apologize to Haruka, whoever she is!
내가 나중에 하루카란 애한테 사과하면 되잖아요
No need for that.
사과하지 않아도 괜찮습니다
Don't be mistaken! This store is owned by a girl named...
착각하지 말아요
이 가게는 말이죠 하루카란 이름의…
YAKISOBA HARUKA
볶음국수 하루카
Haruka Ijuuin is my name.
"이쥬인 하루카"는
내 이름입니다
IJUUIN
이쥬인
You could have told me that earlier!
빨리 좀 말해 주시지
What's up? The forecast is wrong again!
어떻게 된 거야?
일기 예보랑 다르잖아
Well...
나 참…
Why is it raining?!
왜 비가 오는 거야
What's up with that face?!
얼굴이 왜 그모양이냐?
It's nothing to laugh about!
웃을 일이 아니잖아!
By the way...
He is Gaku...
덧붙여…
가쿠입니다...
That's right!
옳으신 말씀!
But this rain is too sudden!
하지만 이번 비는 너무 갑작스러운 걸
Really...
정말이야…
Could it be?!
-설마?!
Punishment of Kappa?
캇파의 벌?
(Kappa: mythical water-dwelling creature that looks like a child)
No way!
일 리가 없지
It's obvious!
당연하잖아
-What is?
-What do you want?
-뭐야?
-뭐가?
If you have complaints then pay the debt!
불만있으면 빚이나 갚아
Monster typhoon?
도깨비 태풍?
Right. It appeared without any indications.
그래요, 아무런 조짐도 없이 나타나서
It looks like it's going to bring a big disaster, but then it suddenly yet mysteriously disappears.
커다란 재해를 일으킬 듯 하다가 다시 돌연 사라져버리는 의문의 괴현상
It happened five times around the world in this month.
요 한달동안 세계 각지에서 5번이나 발생했습니다
-Don't you watch any news?
-Blah-blah.
-넌 뉴스도 안 보냐?
-시끄러
The festival is probably going to be canceled.
이 상태라면 학원제는 중지구만
The monster typhoon that happened in America is told to have stayed at one place for 3 days.
미국에서 발생한 도깨비 태풍은 한곳에 3일간이나 머물러 있었다고 들었어
Sheesh, I spent my precious time doing rehearsals with Ms. Maria!
젠장, 모처럼 마리아 씨와 리허설까지 했구만
Like Shin said, the worst is yet to come.
신 말대로, 최악의 사태가 발생할 수도 있어
I guess the vice principal is disappointed too.
교감 선생님도 낙심하셨겠죠
Huh? Say, where is Haruka?
어레? 그러고보니 하루카는?
He said that he'll stay at the booth all night.
교감 선생님이라면
판매대를 철야로 지킨다고 하셨어
What?!
뭐라고?
I guess you don't know anything at all.
정말, 아무것도 모르는군요
His yakisoba is the special product of the festival.
교감 선생님의 볶음국수는 학원제의 명물이라구요
He's definitely not going to give it up.
포기하실 수 없겠지요
Every year, he risked his life for that one.
교감, 매년 그거에 목숨 걸었으니까 말이지
Too bad for him.
좀 안됐어…
What?!
아니?!
What is it?
무슨 일이야?
-Ryu's in danger.
-Understood. I'll be right there.
-류가 위험해
-알았어, 바로 갈게
I'm looking forward to your yummy yakisoba!
맛나는 볶음국수, 기대할게요!
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Original Korean Subtitles by Jaebari (재바리)
Translated to English by Subdivers
Checked by Great Exkaiser103
자막 원본(번역): 재바리
수정: Subdivers
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Now!
지금이다!
Mecha-beast Fusion!
기수합체
(機獸合體)
Shadow Dagwon!
섀도우 다그온
What is this guy?
뭐지, 이녀석은?
Are you alright, Shadow Dagwon?
괜찮아, 섀도우 다그온?
I guess so...
그, 그럭저럭…
However, this is no common typhoon!
하지만 이건 평범한 태풍이 아니야!
What?!
뭐라고?!
It definitely isn't right.
확실히 이상하군요
Typhoons in the northern hemisphere including Japan rotate counterclockwise because of the rotation of the Earth.
일본을 시작해, 북반구에 발생하는 태풍은 지구 자전의 영향으로 시계 반대방향으로 돕니다
But this typhoon is rotating clockwise. This is impossible!
하지만 이 태풍은 시계 방향으로 돌고 있어요 이런 현상은 있을 수 없어요!
If then...!
그렇다면…!
You're right, Dagwon gentlemen.
그 말대로다, 다그온 제군
My name is Futtoba Seijin.
내 이름은 훗토바 성인
I will sweep out the inferior civilization of Earth with my great power!
나의 위대한 힘으로 지저분한 지구의 문명을 모조리 쓸어버려 주마!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체
(融合合體)
Dag Fire!
다그 파이어
Super Chaining Fusion!
초중련합체
(超重連合體)
Super Liner Dagwon!
슈퍼 라이너 다그온
Big Shadow Shuriken!
섀도우 대 수리검!
Turbo Wheel Cutter!
터보 호일 커터!
Fire Blaster!
파이어 블래스터!
Do your worst!
소용없다, 소용없어!
-Principal?
-Yes?
-교장 선생님
-예이?
Why don't you take that face off?
그 얼굴, 그만 빼시죠?
That's right. I'll take it off.
그렇군요, 그럼 빼겠습니다
Then how's this?!
그럼 이건 어떠냐?!
You're not bad, Tobe. Then how's this?!
토베 양, 제법이구나
그럼, 이런 건 어떠냐?!
You'll have to do better than that!
아직이예요, 이정도 쯤이야~
It's Dagwon!
다그온이다!
Dagwon is fighting against the typhoon!
다그온이 태풍과 싸우고 있어!
This sudden monstrous typhoon is striking a number of towns with its lightening.
갑자기 발생한 이 기괴한 태풍은 격렬한 번개를 내뿜으며 마을을 차례차례 파괴하고 있습니다
Dagwon is minimizing the damage, but it seems that they are having a tough fight.
다그온이 피해를 최소한으로 막고 있습니다만 상당히 고전하고 있는 것 같습니다
Don't lose, Dagwon! Destroy the typhoon!
지지마라, 다그온!
태풍 따윈 해치워버려!
That's right! Our school festival is in your hands!
그래! 학원제가 걸려 있으니까!
Go! Dagwon!
힘내라 다그온! 힘내라 다그온!
힘내라 다그온! 힘내라 다그온! 힘내라 다그온!
힘내라 다그온!
Hmph, I see you haven't given up yet.
흥, 단념하지 않은 모양이군
Yakisoba is waiting for me!
볶음국수가 날 기다리고 있다!
Miniskirts sisters too!
미니스커트 누님도 말이지!
Damn, where is its weak point?!
젠장, 녀석의 약점은 어디지?!
The core of this alien must be the center of the typhoon!
우주인의 본체는 분명 태풍의 중심
In other words, I'm betting for the eye of the typhoon.
다시말해, 태풍의 눈을 겁니다
If we hit there...
그곳을 공격하면…
The eye of the typhoon?
태풍의 눈?
The 15th Typhoon is still heading north...
태풍 15호는 북쪽을 향하고 있으며…
I see!
그렇구나!
Dag Wing, where is the real typhoon?
다그 윙, 진짜 태풍은 지금 어딨지?
Wa- wait for a moment.
기, 기다려 주세요
On the pacific ocean, 100km to the southeast.
여기에서 100Km정도 남동쪽에 위치한 태평양 위입니다
What are you planning?
대체 어쩔 셈이지?
An eye for an eye!
눈에는 눈…이란 녀석이다!
I see! You're going to hit the real typhoon!
과연! 진짜 태풍에 부딪치는 거군요
I'll be able to play occult with Ms. Maria!
이걸로 내일은 마리아 씨와 오컬트 놀이를…
(Maria's nose is itchy because someone said her name)
Did I catch a cold?
감기 걸렸나?
Everything is because of that monster typoon!
이것도 저것도 모두 그 도깨비 태풍 때문이야!
Dagwon! Get rid of that brat!
다그온! 그런 녀석, 해치워버려!
Armor Buster!
아머 버스터!
Shadow Gun Beam!
섀도우 건 빔!
Still didn't get it?
아직도 모르겠느냐?
You cannot take me down!
너희들은 날 해치울 수 없다!
You idiots, do you think you can run away?
바보 놈들, 도망칠 수 있을 거라 생각하나?
I'm counting on you, Shadow Dagwon, Super Liner Dagwon!
부탁한다 섀도우 다그온!
슈퍼 라이너 다그온!
It's not going to let us go.
우리을 놓칠 것 같지 않아 보이는군
Yeah, as we expected.
그래, 이쪽 생각대로야
Why not give up already, Dagwon?
이제 그만 단념하는 게 어떠냐, 다그온?
That's it!
저거다!
Hiding there won't do anything!
그런 곳에 숨어도 소용없다!
We got it!
걸렸다!
Wh- what the heck... is going on?!
이, 이건 대체…
어떻게 된 거지?!
Look! The typhoon is decreasing!
봐! 태풍이 점점 작아지고 있어
Our plan worked! It showed itself!
작전 성공이야!
녀석이 정체를 드러냈어
Now, Dag Fire!
지금이다, 다그 파이어!
Got it!
좋았어!
Strength Fusion!
강력합체
(剛力合體)
Power Dagwon!
파워 다그온
Infinity Cannon!
무한포!
Target Lock!
타깃 록(TARGET LOCK)!
Set on!
세트 온(SET ON)!
Fire!
발사(FIRE)!
Dear departed souls of the afterlife, appear before me!
황천의 망령들이여… 내 앞에 나타나거라!
Appear! Appear! Appear!
나와! 나와! 나와!
If I say appear, then appear! Appear! Appear!
나오라면 나와!
나와! 나와!
Sister, someone's waiting for you.
누나, 언제까지 손님을 기다리게 할 셈이야?
Why aren't you appearing?
정말, 왜 안 나오는 거야?!
Just a moment. She'll manage to call the real ghost in no time.
기다려봐 조금만 더 있으면 진짜 귀신을 불러낼 수 있다구
This is no good.
글렀구만, 이거
It tastes really good.
정말 좋은 향이군
It's really fortunate that the school festival didn't get canceled.
정말 다행이예요 학원제가 중지되지 않아서요
Truly, it's a relief.
정말 다행이야, 다행~
Th- thank you so much.
가, 감사…합니다
Miss, have we met before?
누님, 전에 어디서 만난 적 없던가요?
Oh, it wasn't me?
부르시지 않았군요;;
Excuse me.
이거 실례했습니다
You're working, Shin.
일하는 중이야, 신
I think I saw that look from back...
어디서 본 적이 있는데, 저 뒷모습
Let's go, Luna.
가자, 루나
Thank you so much.
감사합니다
Oh, I'm out of soy sauce.
간장이 떨어졌군요
I'll go buy some.
잠깐 사와야겠습니다
This is the famed Haruka's yakisoba!
이게 소문의 "하루카의 볶음국수"구만!
Let's eat!
잘먹겠습니다~
It's so good!
맛있구만~
This must be a hit!
이거 잘 나가겠는데?
Of course it is.
당연하지요
Uh, that is... um...
아니, 이건 그… 저기…
How impolite it is, to eat stealthily.
몰래 먹다니, 정말 괘씸하군요
As a punishment,
벌로…
As a punishment...
벌로……
You will have to eat all that yakisoba.
그 볶음국수를 모두 드셔야겠습니다
I'll respond to that by doing so!
책임지고 먹어주마!
It tastes too good, Haruka!
엄청 맛있다, 하루카~
The sun suddenly called me
태양이 갑작스레 나를 불러내서
taiyou ga fui ni ore wo izanau
To come to the blue sea
푸르게 비치는 바다로 만나러 갔지
aoku sukitooru umi ni ai ni kita
The ripples are coming and going
밀려왔다 돌아가는 잔물결
yosete wa kaesu sazanami
An endless melody
멈추지 않는 멜로디
tomaru koto nai MELODY
To keep that shape for eternity
그 모습을 영원히 유지할 수 있도록
sono sugata towa ni tsunagu you ni
I'll follow the fate of the dream
꿈의 행방을 뒤쫓아 갈 거야
oikakete yuku yo yume no yukue
Sparkling far away
멀리서 반짝이던
tooku kirameita
A Prism in the Wind
바람 속의 프리즘
kaze no naka no PRISM
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Preview for Next Episode
용자지령
다그온
차회예고
We can't deal with this guy!
이녀석은 당해낼 수 없어!
A strong beam is aiming at us from the other side of the sky.
강력한 빔이 하늘 저편에서 우리을 저격해왔어
No matter how far up we go, the beam keeps getting higher!
아무리 상공으로 올라가도 빔은 훨씬 더 위에서 날아온다구!
Finally, we've reached the stronghold with the enemy robot!
적 로봇과 함께 나는 거대한 요새에 도착했어!
That place is... in Space?!
그곳은… 우주 공간!
Really, En?! Did you go to Space?!
정말이냐, 엔?!
우주에 가버린 거냐?!
Next time on Yuusha Shirei Dagwon! En Fights in the Stratosphere
다음회 용자지령 다그온
엔, 성층권에서 싸우다
And a mysterious space shuttle appeared!
그리고 수수께끼의 스페이스 셔틀이 출연했다!
En Fights at the Stratosphere
엔, 성층권에서 싸우다